Faizan Shahid

Electrical Engineer

 $\,\,{}^{\bigcirc}\,$ H. No. 137, St. No. 05 East, Shabbir Lane, Rawalpindi.

+92-321-9941551

in pk.linkedin.com/in/faizanshahid

sh.faizanshahid

Summary

Diligent electrical engineer with over 1 year professional experience in the fertilizer industry, executing the operation, maintenance and overhauling activities, observing HSE guidelines. Potential to work in a competitive environment, achieving the desired targets with pace, exceeding expectations. Capable in managerial and business aptitudes with proven project management, communication, leadership and interpersonal abilities.

Work History

Assistant Engineer - Electrical & Instrument

Sep 2017 - Feb 2018

Fatimafert Limited (formerly DH Fertilizers Limited), Fatima - Group, Lahore.

- Executed maintenance, overhauling and installation activities of electrical and instrumentation equipment at Ammonia, Urea and Utility units, ensuring reliable plant operation.
- Evaluated electrical machines, switch-gear and instrumentation equipment performances, reviewing necessary alteration and revision, satisfying the HSE and ISO standards by performing Job Safety Analysis (JSA) and Job Cycle Check (JCC) Activities.
- Standardized description of electrical and instrumentation equipment as part of STRUXTURE software in collaboration with SPHERA organization.
- Trained personnel of E&I workshop on Process Safety Management (PSM), leading technical and safety meetings.

Graduate Trainee Engineer - Electrical

Aug 2016 - Sep 2017

Fatimafert Limited (formerly DH Fertilizers Limited), Fatima - Group, Lahore.

- Accomplished Work Procedures and Preventive Maintenance Planning project of HT, LT motors along with starters and switch-gear within the committed time span.
- Prepared maintenance reports and learned overhauling procedures of electrical machines and instrumentation equipment.
- Attained training about power generation through steam & gas turbines and distribution through substations and feeders. Learned operation and protections of generators, motors, transformers and other electrical instruments.

Intern - Testing Services

July 2015 - Aug 2015

Schlumberger, Islamabad.

- Furnished verified record of Oil and Gas bottles after performing pressure tests and analyzing maintenance log sheets, accounting units and assets list.
- Prepared Service Delivery Procedures and learned about the operation and maintenance of all the machines and designing of Piping & Instrumentation Diagrams.

Education

Bachelor of Electrical Engineering

Sep 2012 - Jun 2016

National University of Sciences and Technology, Islamabad.

- C.G.P.A: 3.38/4.00.
- Final Year Project THERM CHARGE:
 - Electricity generation from waste heat energy sources and sunlight at maximum efficiency. Priority-based load sharing battery charge controller, utilizing the two renewable energy sources and main AC supply.

Higher Secondary School Certificate

2010 - 2012

F. G. Sir Syed College, Rawalpindi.

• Percentage: 86.73%.

Secondary School Certificate

2008 - 2010

The Grammar Foundation Higher Secondary School, Rawalpindi.

• Percentage: 95.14%

Computer Skills

- Professional Software:
 - Microsoft Office
 - AutoCAD
 - MATLAB
- Engineering Software:
 - Proteus Design Suite
 - LabVIEW
 - OrCAD PSPICE
 - Advanced Design System
 - Atmel Studio
 - Visual Studio

• Programming Languages:

- C, C++ Language
- Assembly Language
- VHDL

Awards and Achievements

- Final Year Project nomination for Rector's Gold Medal Award.
- Final Year Project funding/sponsorship by National Development Complex, NESCOM.
- Finalist of Finding Innovative and Creative Solutions for Society 2015 & 2016 competition.
- Completion of Community Services Course.
- NUST Performance-Based and Merit-Based Scholarship.
- Attended 12th National Summer Camp for talented boys organized by the Inter Board Committee of Chairpersons.
- Merit-Based Scholarship by Federal Board of Intermediate and Secondary Education.

Extra-Curricular Activities

- Member of Fatima-Group Employee Volunteer Program for Youth Education under CARE Foundation.
- Participated in Photography Competition organized by FFT management.
- Organized Sports Gala and Teachers in Service program at SAYA School.
- Participant of Brand Yourself Workshop organized by Fatima-Group.
- Deputy Director Logistics of TABA Youth Chapter, NUST.
- Executive Member of Association for Computing Machinery, NUST.